<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codesmithery par Excellence</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4747/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>http://localhost:4747</link>
    <description>My little blog. Perpetual work-in-progress</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>re-write</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4747/articles/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4747/articles/0/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased to debut my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; blog, which is made with Grunt and Wintersmith, as opposed to Middleman. I’ve decided for a while now that I want to move away from Ruby and do more Javascript. So lets talk about how I made the migration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s helpful, firstly, to understand the analogy between my old site and the new. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Software&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Old&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;New&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;language&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ruby&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;JS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;package manager&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bundle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Npm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;make tool&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rake&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grunt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;static site generator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Middleman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wintersmith&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;template engine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slim&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jade&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;from-ruby-to-javascript&quot;&gt;from Ruby to Javascript&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby is nice and all- it’s my daily craft after all. But I can’t help but feel that Ruby (and Rails) is on the slow decline. There seems to me, an inevitable destiny that JS will rule the world. But I find that with Javascript comes a lot of extra baggage in my code. Ruby gets right to the point with it’s sweet DSL’s but with Javascript usually has a more distracting bits. It’s nearly as nice as Ruby, but it is ultimately more flexible and can be made into a much more pleasant language with extensions such as underscore.js. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;from-bundle-to-npm&quot;&gt;from Bundle to Npm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much to say here. Just some slightly difference commands to learn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;from-rake-to-grunt&quot;&gt;from Rake to Grunt&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rake and Grunt are very different. Grunt seems more “focused” than Rake- Rake is fundamentally script whereas Grunt is fundamentally configuration. Grunt definetly lays down rails for you to make things easy where Rake is just a thin layer between you and some Ruby. I like Grunt a lot and, truth be told, I never really liked Rake to begin with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;from-middleman-to-wintersmith&quot;&gt;from Middleman to Wintersmith&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the hardest tool to pick but I’m &lt;em&gt;loving&lt;/em&gt; wintersmith. It takes a bunch of files, some configurations and plugins and outputs a website. I started with something like Jekyll but frankly, Jekyll was way to restrictive for me, which was why I switched to Middleman. Heckle would be the JS equivelant to Jeckle but like I said, I was looking for something more robust than a straight blog generator. Wintersmith also lets you embed code right in your html which I think is very cool. I really don’t understand the appeal of logic-less html. Sure, keep you business logic in the model but a view can have it’s own logic. And the ability to call upon the entirety of Javascript right in your html is just too tempting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;from-slim-to-jade&quot;&gt;from Slim to Jade&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slim as another of my favorite Ruby pieces and I’m glad an equivelant exist in the JS world. Jade is is just groovy- real JS mixed with minimal html markup. Just remember that in contrast to Haml, you must escape the content of your html.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>